Mello, Michael; Papers apap287
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Research Files, 1800-2004; 7; 14 cubic ft.
  - Submission of the National Legal Aid and Defender Association to the Ad Hoc Committee of the Judicial Conference of the United States on Federal Habeus Corpus Review in Capital Cases by Louis Bilionid, 1989 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 49)
  - "Sudden Recall: Adult Memories of Child Abuse Spark a Heated Debate" by Bruce Bower, 1993 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 50)
  - Summaries of Juvenile Defendant Cases, Undated (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 51)
  - Summary of Professor Yackle's Statement, 1990 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 52)
  - Summary of Remarks of Judge Donald P. Lay, Chief Judge of the 8th Circuit Court of Appeals, Undated (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 53)
  - Summary of the Repor of the AD Hoc Committee on Federal Habeus Corpus in Capital Cases, 1989 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 54)
  - Summary of Statement of Davud I. Bruck, 1991 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 55)
  - "Support for the Death Penalty Remains High at 74% Slight Majority Prefers Death Penalty to Life Imprisonment as Punishment for Murder" by Jeffrey M. Jones, 2003 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 56)
  - The Supreme Court Leading Cases, 1987 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 57)
  - Supreme Court of Ohio- Report of the Committee on the Appointment of Consel For Indigent Defendants in Capital Cases, 1990 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 58)
  - "Taking Supreme Court Opinions Seriously" by Henry P. Monaghan, 1979 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 59)
  - "Taking Women as a Starting Point: Building Women's Law" by Tove Stang Dahl, 1986 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 60)
  - "The tattered Cloak of Immortality" by Audrey K. Gordon, 1986 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 61)
  - "Teaching Feminist Legal Theory at Texas, Listening to Difference and Exploring Connections" by Patricia A. Cain, 1988 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 62)
  - Teague v. Lane, 1987-1988 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 63)
  - "Testimony Death Penalty for Juveniles in Kentucky Concerning House Bill 392" by Victor L. Streib, 1988 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 64)
  - "Theorising about Theorising" by Dale Spender, ca.1983 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 65)
  - "The Theory of Judicial Decision" by Roscoe Pound, 1923 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 66)
  - Thomas v. Kemp, 1986 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 67)
  - Thomas v. Kemp, 1986 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 68)
  - Thompson v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 69)
  - "Thurgood Marshall and the Administration of Criminal Justice: An Analysis of Dissenting Opinions" by William J. Daniels, 1978 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 70)
  - "Thurgood Marshall and the Forgotten Legacy of Brown v. Board of Education: by Kenneth F. Ripple, 1980 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 71)
  - "Time and Death in Adolescence " by Rober Kastenbaum, 1959 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 72)
  - Tison v. Arizona, 1985 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 73)
  - Title M: Proceedings After Judgement Article ,440, Undated (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 74)
  - Title VI, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 75)
  - Title VI, VII, IX Cases, 1985; 1990; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 76)
  - Title VI Relief from Victim- Based Discrimination in Capital Sentencing by A. Darwin Holder, Jr., 1989 (Box 13 (7-Research Files), Folder 77)
  - Toles v. Jones, 1990 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - "Too Young to Die- Juveniles and the Death Penalty- A Better Alternative to Killing Our Children: Youth Empowerment" by Sheri Jackson, 1996 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)
  - "Toward a Theory of Law and Patriarchy" by Diane Polan, 1982 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 3)
  - "Toward Neutral Principles of Constitutional Law" by Herbert Wechsler, 1959 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 4)
  - "Towards a Feminist Jurisprudence" by Ann C. Scales, 1981 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 5)
  - "Towards a Methodology for Feminist Research" by Maria Miles, ca. 1983 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 6)
  - "Towards a Recognition of the Necessity for Defense for Politcal Protestors" by Matthew Lippman, 1991 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 7)
  - "Transcendental Nonsense, Metaphoric Reasoning and the Cognitive Stakes for Law" by Steven L. Winter, 1989 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 8)
  - Treaty Senes- Treaties and International Agreements Registered or Filed and Recorded with the Secretariat of the United Nations, Volume 999, 1983 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 9)
  - "Tribute to Justice Thurgood Marshall" by William J. Brennan, Jr., 1987 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 10)
  - Turner v. Florida, 1988 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 11)
  - Tyson v. Tyson, 1985 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 12)
  - "Unconscious Racism and the Criminal Law" by Sheri Lynn Johnson, 1988 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 13)
  - Uniform Laws Annotated- Matrimonial, Family and Health Laws, 1979 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 14)
  - United Nations- Economic and Social Council- Report on Capital Punishment, 1973 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 15)
  - The United States Law Week, 1987 December 1 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 16)
  - The United States Law Week, 1988 May 31 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 17)
  - University of California Regents v. Bakke, 1978 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 18)
  - "'Unusual' Punishment: The Domestic Effecta of International Norms Restricting the Application of the Death Penalty" by Joan F. Hartman, 1983 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 19)
  - "Upon Rereading Mr.Justice Black on the First Amendment" by Harry Kalven, Jr., 1967 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 20)
  - "An Urgent Plea for Help from the Alabama State Bar" by Dennis N. Balske, 1986 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 21)
  - U.S. Codes, Education and Food and Drugs, 1988 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 22)
  - US Supreme Court Orders, 2004 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 23)
  - U.S. v. Allen, 2004 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 24)
  - U.S. Jaycees v. Chicago Jr. Ass'n of Commerce, 1981 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 25)
  - U.S. v. Baldi, 1953 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 26)
  - U.S. v. Chandler ( 1 of 2), 1992 (Box 14 (7-Research Files), Folder 27)
  - U.S. v. Chandler ( 2 0f 2), 1992 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - U.S. v. Cooper, 1991 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)
  - U.S. v. Pretlow, 1991 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 3)
  - U.S. v. Theriault, 1971 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 4)
  - U.S. v. Villarreal, 1991 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 5)
  - "The Value of Quantitative Methodology For Feminist Research" by Toby Epstein Jayaratne, ca. 1983 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 6)
  - Vesecky v. Vesecky, 1995 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 7)
  - "Violence Against Women" in Ms. The World of Women, 1990 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 8)
  - "Violence Juvenile Deliquents" by Lewis et al., 1979 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 9)
  - Virginia v. Stockton, 1988 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 10)
  - "'Waiving' Goodbye to Juvenile Defendants, Getting Smart vs. Getting Tough" by Cynthia R. Noon, 1994 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 11)
  - "Walking the Edge of Death: An Annotated Bibliography on Juveniles, Mentally Ill, The Mentally Retarded and the Death Penalty" by Susan M. Boland, 2001 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 12)
  - Wallance v. Kemp, 1985 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 13)
  - Walton v. Arizona, 1989 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 14)
  - Washington v. Davis, 1976 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 15)
  - Waterhouse v. Florida, 1988 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 16)
  - " Ways of Criticizing the Court" by Frank H. Easterbook, 1982 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 17)
  - Welch v. Beto, 1966 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 18)
  - "Where We Stand: Observations on the Situation of Feminist Legal Thought" by Clare Dalton, 1987 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 19)
  - White v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 20)
  - "Who Decides" by Paul Brest, 1985 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 21)
  - Why We Need the Great Writ: The Role of Federal Habeus Corpus in Protecting Life and Liberty by Foran et al, Undated (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 22)
  - Wilkins v. Missouri, 1987-1988 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 23)
  - Williams v. Lynaugh, 1987 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 24)
  - Williams v. Martin, 1980 (Box 15 (7-Research Files), Folder 25)
  - Wards Cove Packing Co., Inc. v. Atonio, 1989 (Box 16 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - Woman's Constitution" by Kenneth L. Karst, 1984 (Box 16 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)
  - "Women's Law: An Introduction to Feminist Jurisprudence" by Tove Stang Dahl, 1987 (Box 16 (7-Research Files), Folder 3)
  - Zeigler, Undated (Box 16 (7-Research Files), Folder 4)
- Subject Files, 1977-2006; 8; 1 cubic ft.
  Series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series consists of materials related to Michael Mellos work as a professor at Vermont Law School, general correspondence, material related to Michael Mellos medical malpractice suit, and biographical material.
  - Correspondence- General, 1986-1990 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- General, 1991-1994; 1996-1997; 2002; 2005-2006; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Epigrams (1 of 2), Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Epigrams (2 of 2), Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Holland and Knight Invoice, 1987 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Michael Mello- Application to the Bar + DC Court of Appeals Restricted, 1984; 1987 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Michael Mello- Malpractice Suit Against Dr. Cohen, 1997 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Michael Mello- Resume and List of Publications, Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Paul Magill - Resentencing Exhibit Signed by Cast, 1987 (Oversized 1)
  - Photographs, 1977-1979; 1986; 1995; 1998-1999; 2001 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 1 (1 of 2), Fall, 1990 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 1 (2 of 2), Fall, 1990 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 2 (1 of 3), Fall, 1990 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 2 ( 2 of 3), Fall, 1990 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 2 (3 of 3), Fall, 1990 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Vermont Law School- Lawsuit (1 of 2) RESTRICTED, 1998 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Vermont Law School- Lawsuit (2 of 2) RESTRICTED, 1998 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Vermont Law School- Presentation, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Vermont Law School- Seminar: The Death Penalty- Syllabus, Fall, 1994 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)